

#### SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

1006 Cordova Way Kelowna, BC. Canada

□ (+1) 250-215-7408 | wade.t.johnson@gmail.com | & computerrivet.github.io | □ computerrivet | □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/wade-johnson-785925a

"The best way to predict the future is to invent it. - Alan Kay"

# Summary \_\_\_\_

I am a dedicated, hard-working, team-oriented Senior Software Developer with years of industry experience designing, building, and enhancing software applications written in various languages. I enjoy refactoring and modernizing legacy code to a state where it can bring the most value. I love continuous integration and optimized developer workflows.

# Skills\_

General Software Architecture, Build and Deployment Pipelines, Modernizing Legacy Software, Technical Writing

**Languages** Javascript/Typescript, C#, Go, Rust, Python, Shell

Web HTML, CSS, React, Angular, ASP.NET WebForms, NodeJS, KnockoutJS

Databases Firestore, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL, Redis, Neo4J

Mobile React Native, Android

**Build** Github Actions, Jenkins, Gitlab

**OS** Windows, Mac, Linux

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### AAA Internet Publishing Inc. (DBA WTFast)

Kelowna, BC. Canada

Sept. 2019 - Jan. 2024

- Designed and implemented foundational network and project structure in Google Cloud using Terraform.
- Maintained Windows Client build system on Jenkins.
- Designed new Windows Client build system on Github Actions.
- Created a custom deployment system for the Windows Client VueJs application.
- Introduced and deployed a Prometheus metrics monitoring solution.
- Created Github Actions deployment pipeline for building software for routers.
- Deployed a Go proxy (Athens) that was critical to transitioning the company to Github.
- Maintained custom Go OAuth2 server.
- Create SAML token verification server for an important partner.
- Created a server based oauth2 client authentication system for a partner.
- · Created Go authentication middleware that which allowed the the elimination of Cloud Endpoints.
- Ported embedded browser from CefSharp to WebView2 browser engines.
- Ported gRPC server to ConnectRPC so web clients could be used.
- Created a websocket server to push client device authorizations.
- Created an example nDPI packet dissector.

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

Atomic 47 Labs Kelowna, BC. Canada

• Designed high level deployment architecture to optimize cost on Amazon Web Services.

- Designed a Discord chat bot implemented with Node, is and Dokku.
- · Mentored junior developers in technical architecture and problem solving.
- Performed Operations tasks such as OS platform, networking, and DNS Management.

FEBRUARY 7, 2024 WADE JOHNSON · RÉSUMÉ

Aug. 2018 - Oct. 2019

# Maplecake Software Corp. (Contr. for Do Some Good Community Contribution Company Inc.)

Kelowna, BC. Canada

Oct. 2017 - Aug. 2018

FOUNDER / SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Implemented features and bug fixes for a React web application and React native mobile app.
- Implemented compiler (lexer and parser) for custom markup language used in posting.

#### Maplecake Software Corp. (Contr. for Das Reboot Services Inc.)

Kelowna, BC. Canada Jan. 2015 - Aug. 2017

FOUNDER / SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- Performed upgrade from TFS (Team Foundation Server) 2012 to 2015.
- Performed upgrade for application reports to ActiveReports 10.
- Managed TLS certificate procurement and installation.
- Corrected out of memory issue that caused slow application startup time.
- Corrected Lucene indexing issues with the ERP ServiceCentre application.
- Corrected issues and added features for the Equipment Quoting application used nationwide in Canada.
- Added TransUnion Credit Reporting service into ERP (DealerLink) Credit Application.
- Refactored deployment tool (SyncInfo).
- Corrected bugs and added features to internal ERP applications.
- Started documentation project for ERP DealerLink Installation.
- Wrote FSharp application to remove weblogs periodically.

### Maplecake Software Corp. (Contr. for TheDrillBook Inc.)

Calgary, AB. Canada Dec. 2013 - Nov. 2015

FOUNDER / SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- · Added features and bug fixes to the primary web application for teaching hockey.
- Implemented an email processing system.
- Introduced Jira issue tracking software to the company and designed a custom development workflow for tracking ticket completion.
- Introduced Jenkins build server for building mobile applications.
- · Mentored and trained QA and junior developers.
- Introduced HockeyApp for implementing a beta test program for the mobile application.

#### Maplecake Software Corp. (Contr. for Sunexo Solutions, Inc.)

Calgary, AB. Canada Dec. 2013 - Nov. 2014

FOUNDER / SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Managed deployment of the company application IRIS.

- Deployed SQL Server schema changes to support IRIS.
- Deployed Tableau workbooks to application server.

Pentiction, BC. Canada **Big Bear Software Inc.** 

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jul. 2013 - Oct. 2013

- Performed bug fixes on web application for Sprockets manufacturer.
- Worked on team to implement an Oil and Gas pilot project.

Kelowna FlightCraft Kelowna, BC. Canada

PROGRAMMER/ANALYST

Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2013

- Maintained Lawson M3 plugins that automate workflows.
- · Maintained QlikView documents for business intelligence.

#### Sonic Solutions, Rovi Corp., Corel Corp.

Santa Clara, CA. USA

WER DEVELOPER

Jan. 2010 - Jan. 2013

- Implemented Jenkins based deployment system for WebCore projects.
- Migrated Roxio project for Pinnacle Systems marketing website to .NET 4.0.
- Designed and implemented a marketing campaign email system.
- Designed and implemented a purchase system used by the Sales team to distribute not for resale licenses.
- Implemented a new XML format for the Roxio Product Registration web service that added new messaging and localization.
- Designed and implemented an AJAX enabled press syndication page.
- Implemented device search and registration page for Retrospect integration.
- Implemented video playback for RoxioNow division.
- Implemented Purchase Validation Proxy Web Service.

FEBRUARY 7, 2024 WADE JOHNSON · RÉSUMÉ SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan. 2008 - Dec. 2009

- Developed a component that gathered language statistics for neural net scoring.
- Designed and implemented REST-based web services that supported a single page web application providing English language feedback (tutoring) and scoring.
- Designed and implemented a continuous integration server to build software.
- Implemented web-based drill-down reports for Benchmark Tracker.

Graniterock Company Watsonville, CA. USA

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jun. 2007 - Dec. 2007

- Created and maintained build scripts for Visual Studio Team System.
- · Implemented and deployed a document management system to track customer receipts.

AMERISAFE, Inc. Deridder, LA. USA

Business Analyst, Analyst / Programmer III

Dec. 2001 - Jun. 2007

- Designed and implemented a digital dashboard application.
- Maintained the primary OLAP analysis application.
- Developed a custom alerting system for emailing reports.
- Lead a team that designed and implemented an performance sensitive application that transferred claims documents to a processing company.
- Implemented customization scripts for document scanning and indexing for the Vignette document management system.
- Designed and implemented a system to make the custom ERP (ICAMS) scalable to hundreds of users using the embedded Foxpro database.

## **Education**

#### **Northwestern State University**

Natchitoches, LA, USA

B.S. IN COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS AND BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Aug. 1997 - Dec. 2001